JAMES WOLFE

✓ Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com

☐ (703)789-0919

☐ Website Portfolio

SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in programming and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment, AWS Cloud, web development, Linux, and computer technology troubleshooting.

SKILLS

o Computer Troubleshooting o Joomla & WordPress o AWS Cloud o HTML & CSS

o Java-Script o RedHat o Java o SSH

PROJECTS

Portfolios - Database Websites GitHub Repo

- Created and maintained using AWS Cloud services S3 and Route53, Azure Storage Container with respective HTML, CSS, and Java-script.
- Applied Agile best practices to develop the project while also applying and producing new ideas in the process.

Publishing Services

- Launched on GitHub Pages and Surge utilizing the publishing services through CMD and GitHub to host and maintain the produced websites
- Developed the websites using GitHub community templates, W3Schools, and WordPress editing them using HTML and CSS.

Headless Media Center - Raspberry Pi

- Utilized Volumio after mounting the bootable program to a Raspberry Pi through the Linux based OS and entering Linux commands to connect the Volumio device to the phone application and account.
- Maintained and worked on the device using respective hardware and output the media player through Fender Squier 4 speakers
 connected using respective audio and power cables.

Computer Building and Troubleshooting

- Researched and budgeted computer hardware components and building the box while diagnosing rising issues with the POST sequence and maintained the software and hardware using compressed air, file clean up, and back-ups.
- Repaired computer related problems after diagnosing hardware issues for peers such as, mis-aligned RAM and reseating components.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Woodworker Sue's Antiques

June 2021 — Present

• After purchasing and finding old and damaged antique furniture and items, I refurbish them utilizing sanding and stanning techniques, then resell the 18th and 19th century antiques in a variety of store locations gaining key and professional skills.

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

November 2020 — December 2020

• Server related issues such as, unable to POST and RAID configurations, and after analyzing the issue I diagnose the software or hardware reseating components or rebooting the software through Linux and resolve the ticket, I developed technical skills here required to thrive in a professional work environment.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

June 2018 — January 2019

• While working in a fast-paced environment and multi-tasking, I managed my time effectively and made use of a step-by-step process taking orders, serving food and drinks, and welcoming new customers to provide the best quality customer service.

Sale's Associate PetValu

September 2015 — August 2017

- Faced with nutritional and health related issues for customers pets while working independently, I worked through problems by asking
 pet related questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve a customer concern and did it effectively by
 utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.
- Volunteered with Homeward Trails, German Shepherd Rescue, and PetValu by feeding, cleaning, and playing providing comfort and joy for the pets.

CERTIFICATIONS

EDUCATION

AWS Cloud Practitioner September 2020 — September 2023

Agile Scrum Fundamentals April 2022

ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp March 2022

ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College May 2020